All right!
（ナルト）よ～し！　いよいよ
生態調査　始めっぞ！
I'm going to start on
the ecological survey!
おい！　待てってばよ！
Hey!
Hey wait!
タコのおっさん…　コイツ　オスかメスか
わかんねえんだけど→
Hey Octopops, I can't tell whether
this one's a male or female.
Its body's all curled up.
体が丸まってて。
（キラービー）コイツは昔から→
This armadillo's always been shy.
恥ずかしがりやのアルマジロ。
性別調べるなんて　あるまじき。
If you're trying to check
its gender,
I can see why.
ド変態の大合唱！
これが　人間のスケベな本性！
The chorus sings out about
this super abnormality...
Because now we see
a human's real pervert personality...
しようがねえだろ！
これは　Ｓランクの極秘任務だぞ。
I have no choice!
This is a top-secret
S-rank mission and
俺は　動物部隊のリストを
作んなきゃなんねえんだ。
I have to make the list
for the Animal Unit!
オスかメスか調べんのは
最重要事項なんだってばよ！
And checking for gender is crucial!
どっちでもかまわない。
Male, female, it don't matter.
So just report that it's the latter.
じゃあ　メスってことで
報告　カマしとけ！
でもさ　でもさ
背中んとこに思いっきり→
But! But!
The markings on
the back read "Male."
「男」って書いてあるんだけど。
それは　模様のようだな。
That's just a pattern.
なんか　嫌な予感がすんだけどな。
I just have a bad feeling
about this.
もう…
聞いてみてくれよ　おっさん。
Ask the armadillo will ya,
old man?
ここのボスなんだろ！？
You're the boss here, right?
Well?
どうなんだ？
プライベートはプライバシー！
It says its, "privates are private!"
あ～　そうですか！
Oh, is that right?
Damn it!
How can I do any research?
クソ…　これじゃあ　なかなか
調査進まねえじゃねえか！
さすが　Ｓランク任務！
…なのか？　これ！
This S-rank mission is
living up to its rank... or is it?!
オスとメス
性別ひっくり返るようなことが→
Male and female...
Some species can switch
between both, yo!
あってもＹＯ！　天地が
ひっくり返るわけでもねえだろ。
But heaven and earth
can never switch places, yo!
バカヤロー　コノヤロー。
Fool, ya fool...
《モトイ：なんだ？　何かが
どんどん　近づいてくる！
What?! Something is approaching
at high speed!
これは…　人じゃない》
And it's... not human!
（ヤマト）どうしました？
What's the matter?
♪～
（オオノキ）少々びっくりしたぜ。
You took me by surprise.
死んだと
聞いとったからのう…　デイダラ。
I had heard that
you were dead, Deidara.
まさか　お前の粘土分身とは。
I never expected your clay clones.
（カブト）さっきのは？
（デイダラ）土影の岩分身だ。
So that was...
... a stone clone of the Tsuchikage.
考えてたことは同じだな　うん。
We were thinking
the same thing. Hmm!
（黒ツチ）デイダラ兄！
派手に爆死したはずなのに→
Brother Deidara!
I thought you blew
yourself up in a big way.
なんで　生きてるの！？
（赤ツチ）ハハ！
Why are you still alive?
ホントは死んでなかったダニか？
So you didn't die, after all?
喜ぶな　赤ツチ！
あ…。
Don't get excited, Akatsuchi!
穢土転生とかいう　大蛇丸の術だ。
It's Orochimaru's jutsu,
called the Reanimation Jutsu.
生き返ったように見えとるが
あれも本物じゃあない。
It may seem as though
he was brought back to life,
but he's not real.
まったく…
死んでまで　迷惑をかけおって。
Damn it. Still causing trouble,
even in death!
木ノ葉の青二才にやられ→
A youngster from
the Hidden Leaf beats you...
また　のこのこ生き返ってまで
恥をさらすか！
And then you have the gall
to sneak back in amongst the living!
うるせぇ！
うちはサスケは殺ったはずだ　うん。
Shut up!
I killed Sasuke Uchiha... hmm!
今度は　俺の芸術をバカにしくさった
ジジイ…　お前だ！　うん。
And now it's your turn, geezer,
for mocking my art! Hmm!
《何も知らんようだな　デイダラめ》
Seems Deidara doesn't
know anything.
もういい！　お前らは
わしが捕まえてやる！
Enough! I'll capture you both!
邪魔をして
足止めしてるつもりですか？
Do you intend to get in our way?
待ち伏せは　わかっていましたよ。
I knew we would be ambushed.
何もせず　ここへ
のこのこ来るとでも？
You didn't think we'd come
unprepared, did you?
うっ…　どういう意味じゃ？
What do you mean?
まさか…　もう
ここが　バレたのか？　そんな…。
Impossible! They've found out
about this place already?
Th-There's no way...!
モトイさん…。
Motoi...
ibitsu na merodll de dekita aisareru beki ikimono da
Made from a distorted melody,
I'm a creature that should be loved
seika wa agerarenakute mo kokoro ga utatte iru kara
Even if I can't better myself,
I'll continue to sing from my heart
dore dake tsuyoi ame koete aisareru beki ikimono ka?
What storms must I overcome
To be a creature who should be loved?
yakusoku ga mamorenakute mo kokoro wa utatte iru kedo
Even if you can't keep your promise
My heart will keep on singing, but...
dono doa nokku shite aketara ii?
Which door should I knock on and open?
aketara doko e mukattara ii?
Once I open it, where should I go?
hitori ja kaerenai kara
I can't go home by myself
dareka o matte ita dake
I was just waiting for someone
kimi ga ima ichiban aitai hito wa dare?
Who is the one you want to meet the most?
kokoro no naka de dake hanaseru hito no kazu wa fuete iku
The number of people that I can only speak to in my heart
keep increasing
dakara tsuyoku naritakatta tada
So I just wanted to be strong
bokura mada yomitarinai monogatari
Our story just hasn't been told enough
muriyari owarenai koto wakattete
We know it's not something we can just quit
dare mo mina jibun no mama
Because we all want to be ourselves
tsuyoku naritakatta kara
We wanted to be strong
The Artist Returns
《どうやら見つけたようだね》
Seems we found them.
悪いけど　ここは向こうへ行くよ。
なんでだよ？
Sorry, but we have to go there.
Why?
（デイダラ）って…　なんだ？
おいらの体が　いうこときかねえ。
What? My body won't
respond to me!
No way!
Don't tell me he found them!
まさか　見つかっただと？
（オオノキ）２人とも追うぞ！
（赤ツチ）あい！
We're going after him, you two!
– Right!
– Gotcha!
うわっ…。
なんだってばよ…。
What's going on?
《あらゆる薬を使って→
I used various drugs to activate
the original Manda's cells
マンダの細胞を
活性化させて作った二代目マンダ。
to create a Second Manda...
大きさ　強さ　感知能力は
初代マンダをもしのぐ。
He surpasses the First Manda
in size, power, and intellect!
島が動物で
移動できることが仇になったね》
The fact that the island is
an animal and is mobile
turns out to be its fatal flaw.
（デイダラ）なんだ？　ありゃ。
What is that?
島か…
あの島が　なんだってんだ？
An island?
What's that island supposed to be?
島じゃない。
でかい亀で動いている。
It's not an island.
It's a giant turtle and it's moving.
そして　あそこに
八尾と九尾がいる。
And that is where we'll find
the Eight and Nine Tails.
亀？　しかも　八尾と九尾だと？
A turtle? The Eight and Nine Tails?
八尾と九尾を捕まえるチャンスだ。
This is our chance to capture
the Eight and Nine Tails!
そうか。
I get it! So that damn Naruto
is there! Hmm!
あそこに　ナルトの野郎がいんのか。
うん。　で　どうする？
What's the plan?
とにかく
あの島亀の動きを止める。
In any case,
we have to stop that turtle island.
デイダラ　大きいのを　ひとつ頼む。
Deidara, give me a big one.
クソ…　速いのう。
Damn!
They're fast!
いくよ。
ああ。
Let's go!
Right.
（デイダラ）喝！！
Katsu!
木遁　樹海降誕！
Wood Style:
Deep Forest Emergence!
（デイダラ）ひっくり返ったな。
これで動けねえ。
It flipped over.
It can't move now.
Oww...
イテテ…　何が起きたんだ？
What happened?
（キラービー）本当に
天地が　ひっくり返ったよ。
Heaven and Earth really
did trade places, yo.
バカヤロー　コノヤロー。
Fools, ya fool!
あ～っ！　やっぱり！！
I knew it!
天地　ひっくり返っても
オスは　オス…　と。
Even if Heaven and Earth flip over...
A male is still a male and...
（ヤマト）こんなときに
生態調査してる場合か！！
This is no time to be doing
an ecological survey!
（アオバ）いいから　落ち着くんだ　ヤマト。
あくまで　Ｓランク任務で…。
Calm down, Yamato.
Remember, this is an S-rank mission.
外で　何かあったに違いない。
Something must have
happened outside.
だが　ここは
なんとか　ごまかして…。
But we have to keep fooling him.
２人を絶対に
外へ出してはならない。
We cannot allow those two
to leave this place.
俺たちで　なんとかするんだ。
We have to deal with it ourselves.
カブト　お前は
八尾と九尾を捜せ　うん。
Kabuto, you search for
the Eight and Nine Tails. Hmm...
おいらは　アイツらとやる。
いろいろ借りもあるしな。
I'll handle those guys.
I owe them nothing less.
じゃあ　そうしましょうか。
Fine, let's do that.
デイダラ　わしの恐ろしさを。
Deidara!
You shall feel my wrath.
やべえ　ジジイがキレやがってる。
Damn it, the geezer's snapped.
忘れたわけじゃねえだろう！
You haven't forgotten, have you?
《　ってますます　マジやべえぜ。
This is getting bad!
いきなり
塵遁かましてくる気か　うん》
Don't tell me he's going right
to his Particle Style?! Hmm!
《何やら　やばそうだ》
Things are starting to get out of hand.
《逃がさんぜ！》
I won't let you get away!
何のつもりじゃ　赤ツチ。
What are you doing, Akatsuchi?!
それをやっちゃったら
島亀も殺しちゃうダニ！
If you do that, you'll end up
killing turtle island!
ええい　ややこしい！
Damn!
This is complicated!
デカすぎて　風景にしか見えん！
It's so large that it just looks
like a landscape!
《スキあり》
There's my chance! Hmm!
うん！
喝！
Katsu!
Old man!
ジジイ！
フフフッ。
Akatsuchi's Golem!
赤ツチのゴーレムか。
Still attached to the Tsuchikage I see...
相変わらず土影に
ベタベタくっつきやがって。
邪魔くせえ　うん。
What a nuisance! Hmm!
I should get him away
from this island.
《この島から　引き離すかの…》
あのヘビ野郎！
That damn snake!
あのヘビ操ってんのは
やっぱあっちの野郎か！
So that guy over there is
the one controlling the snake!
大蛇丸の部下だった
モヤシ野郎のくせしやがって！
The nerve of that wimp.
He was just pretending to
be Orochimaru's henchman!
I see...
So Naruto is inside this turtle.
そうかい
ナルトは　この亀の中ってことかい。
さて　となると　入り口は…。
Now then, how do I get in?
Damn it! What's going on outside?!
クソッ　外はどうなってる。
あ！　な　なんか今日は　やけに
大地が落ち着かない日だよね。
Th-There've been
a lot of tremors today...
そ　そうだな。
にしても　変だってばよ。
Y-You're right.
Still, this is too weird.
天地って　ひっくり返るっけ？
Can the world turn upside down?
いや　この島　たまにあるみたいよ。
Well, it seems to be possible
on this island.
非常に珍しい現象だって。
うんうん。
Although it's an extremely rare event.
そうかな。　俺ってば
ちょっと外見てくるってばよ。
Oh really?
I think I'm going to take
a look outside!
い　いや　キミは
大事なＳランク任務中なんだから→
No! You're on
an important S-rank mission,
so stay focused!
だから　任務やりなさい。
いや　だから　ちょっと
外見てくるだけなんだけどさ。
Yeah, well...
I'm just going to take
a quick look outside.
It is a ninja's duty to see through
his mission until completion!
忍者にとって大事なのは
その任務を最後までやり抜くこと。
そして　この任務は他でもない。
And this is a mission
only you can accomplish!
キミだからこそ
キミにしかできない任務。
だから頼まれた。　わかるな　ナルト。
That's why you were selected.
Do you understand, Naruto?
We will see what's going on outside.
外の様子は　僕たちが見てくる。
今の僕たちには
それくらいしかできない。
That's about the only way
we can contribute here.
だが　くれぐれも言う。
However, let me repeat.
お前には大事なＳランク任務が
あるのだぞ！
You are on a crucial S-rank mission!
《さすがにナルトも
何か異変に気がつき始めてる。
Even Naruto is beginning
to sense something.
Ｓランク任務だとハッタリかましたけど→
We bluffed him into thinking
this is an S-rank mission.
やってることは→
But basically,
he's just checking to see
おチンチンがあるかないか
見てるだけだもんなぁ。
if an animal has balls or not.
ナルトもバカじゃない。
もうバレてるんじゃ…》
Naruto's not an idiot.
He might have already
figured it out.
Okay, I understand!
うん　わかった。
俺ってば　任務に集中する。
I'm going to focus on my mission!
《うん！　当分いけるな　こりゃ。
バカでよかった…》
All right!
This is going to work out!
Thank goodness he's so dense!
《おせぇよ！
熔遁　石灰凝の術！》
You're too slow!
Corrosion Style: Quicklime Jutsu!
出てきましたね。
There they are.
アイツか！
人間は　５人いるはずだ。
Is that him?!
There should be five humans!
《アオバもいるのか》
So Aoba is here too.
（黒ツチ）ノコノコ出てくんじゃねえよ！
アタイらで片づける！
Don't come crawling out!
Didn't we say that
we'd take care of this?
《…と　言いつつ》
Having said that...
おっ！　アンタは　たしか土影の孫娘。
You're the Tsuchikage's
granddaughter...
ちょうどいい。
これからナルト君のところまで→
Perfect timing.
You can take me to Naruto.
案内してもらおうか。
A snake...
（ヤマト）蛇…　それに　その声
まさか　お前は…。
And that voice.
Don't tell me you're...
また会ったね　ヤマト。
We meet again, Yamato.
I'll sweep him your way!
そっちへ流す！　捕まえろ！
So get him!
水遁　水喇叭！
Water Style: Water Trumpet!
いいぞ！
Nice!
（アオバ）ダメだ！　読まれてた！
No good! He had it figured out!
I told you guys to get him, but...
《捕まえろ　と言いつつ→
捕まえたぜ》
I got him!
これは…。
This is...
なるほど。
I see...
マヌケ！　テメエは　これで
もう動けねえ！
Idiot! Now you can't move!
《アタイの石灰凝の術は
速効性のセメント。
My Quicklime Jutsu is like
fast-acting cement.
水で流して範囲を広げ→
I spread it around
an area with water...
そして　それは
水に反応して凝固する！》
making it cause a reaction
that makes it harden like cement.
モトイさん　アオバ！
この水を踏まないように！
Motoi, Aoba!
Don't step into that water.
（黒ツチ）更に念には念だ！
That's for extra insurance!
よし！　こうなれば　こっちのもの。
俺が情報を抜き取ります。
All right! You're ours!
I'll extract intel out of you!
《全盛期より速くなってねえか？
じじいのヤツ》
The geezer is faster than
he was in his prime!
お前は昔から
遠距離でコソコソ逃げ回って戦う！
You've always snuck around
and fought from a distance.
わしは　そこが好かん！
I never liked that about you!
うるせぇ！
Shut up!
I'll finish him off with my C4...
Hmm!
《Ｃ４でケリつけてやるぜ　うん》
速すぎて　ついていけないダニ。
They're too fast! I can't keep up!
カブト　落ちたな。
Kabuto, how you've fallen.
ますます
大蛇丸みたいになっちまって…。
You've become just like Orochimaru.
僕のことより
キミが　そこから落ちるなよ。
Never mind me.
Just make sure you don't fall off!
アオバ　集中しろ。
Aoba, concentrate!
ああ　わかってる。　大丈夫だ。
Yeah, I know. I'm okay.
俺が情報部にいることは
知ってるよな？
You know that I'm in
the Intel Division, don't you?
お前に何があったか
すべてを見せてもらう。
I'm going to take a look and see
everything that's happened to you.
うわっ！
あっ！
脱皮！　そこまで！？
He's molted?!
He's gone that far?
モトイ　離れろ！
Motoi, get away!
うわっ！
あっ！
ヤマト！
Yamato!
あっ！
クソ！
Damn it!
（カブト）黒ツチ…　お前の術の手順を
わかっていたおかげで→
Lucky for me, Kurotsuchi, I knew
the hand signs for your jutsu.
うまく油断させることができたよ。
I was able to
put you all off guard.
この機会を
待っていたとでもいうのか！？
Are you saying that
you waited for this moment?
クソ！
Damn!
Corrosion Style: Quicklime Jutsu!
《熔遁・石灰凝の術！》
待て！
Wait!
クソ！　鼻の中に隠れやがって。
Damn! He hid inside the nose!
うわ～！
およ…。
くっ！
《オオノキ：ここまで来れば
ええじゃろう》
This should be high enough.
なめんなよ　ジジイ！
Don't underestimate me,
old geezer!
覚悟せい　デイダラ！
Prepare to die, Deidara!
テメエの塵遁と　俺様の爆遁
どっちが芸術か…。
Let's see which one is real art,
your Particle Style or
my Explosion Style!
これは…。
なんだってんだ！？　いいとこでよ！
This is—?!
What?!
Right when we were getting
to the good part! Hmm!
うん！
クソ！
Damn!
うぅ…　動けない！
I can't move!
（モトイ）待ってろ！
Hold on!
岩隠れの子が戻ったら
助けてもらう。
When the kid from Hidden Rock returns,
she'll free you!
あなたは…　土影様！
You're... Lord Tsuchikage!
デイダラが逃げおった。　そっちは？
Deidara got away.
What about you guys?
岩隠れの方が
追っていきましたが…。
Someone from
the Hidden Rock went after him.
ん！？
ここから　助け出してください！
Please help me!
I'll go after them!
俺が　すぐに追います。
カブトは　どっちに？
Which way did Kabuto go?
敵は　もう感知できない。
どの方向かも　わからない。　ムリだ。
I can't sense the enemy anymore.
I can't tell which direction...
It's useless.
クソ！　ヤマトが…。
Damn it. Yamato's been...
どうしたのじゃ？
What happened?
木遁使い　九尾の見張り役のヤマトが
捕まりました。
The Wood Style user,
the Nine Tails' guardian,
Yamato has been taken.
ふむ…
九尾と八尾まで深追いせずか。
He didn't bother going after
the Eight or Nine Tails.
尋問用の人質目当てか→
We don't know if he wanted
a hostage to interrogate...
その木遁使いが目当てだったかは
わからぬが→
or if the Wood User himself
was the target.
問題は　そのヤマトから
情報が漏れるかもしれんことだ。
But the problem is the intel that
can be gleaned from Yamato!
ヤマトは　簡単に
情報をとられるようなヤツじゃない。
Yamato would never break down
to reveal intel that easily!
そんなこと　言っとんじゃない。
That's not what I meant.
相手がマダラなら　強い瞳術がある。
If our foe is Madara, he will
have formidable visual prowess.
ヤツの瞳術にかかれば
太刀打ちできん。
Once someone is caught
under his visual prowess,
there's no breaking away.
うわっ！
（マダラ）手土産が
かなり違うようだが…。
This present you brought is very
different from what I expected.
確かに　そうだけど→
You're right.
コイツは九尾の見張り役で
機密情報も持ってる。
But he is
the Nine Tails' guardian
and he also possesses
highly classified intel.
それに　コイツがあれば
かなり　ゼツたちを強くできる。
Furthermore, I can use him
to make Zetsu and
the others much stronger.
ムリをするより
コイツを捕らえた時点で→
Instead of pushing my luck,
I decided to settle by
just capturing him.
効率のよいほうを選んだ。
アンタたちにとってね。
This works out better for you guys.
（マダラ）なら　早くしろ。
Then hurry up and do it.
この左目が　戦争を欲している。
This left eye of mine
is itching to battle.
kotae nakute mo ii sa sagashi tsuzukeru n da yo
You don't have to answer, I'll keep on searching
sou otona ni naru jikan da ne
Yeah, I guess it's time to grow up
imasugu tsugetai kedo furue ga tomaranai
I want to tell you right now but I can't stop this shaking
kokoro wa ima sara nigete to sakebu no sa
My heart shouts for me to run away, even now
by my side by my side
By my side, By my side
tatoeba anata no me no oku ni
In the depth of your eyes, if there's a scenery you seek
motomeru keshiki ga aru no nara
sore wo tsukande tashikametai n da
I want to grasp it and see for myself
moshi kimi no namida ga kono sekai wo
If your tears have set you apart from this world
kimi kara toozaketa toshitemo
boku wa sono te hanasanai n da
I won't let go of your hand
dakara sou ima
So, yes... right now
i need you here right by my side
I need you here right by my side
by my side
By my side
Next Episode
Convene the commando unit immediately!
Have the main regiment run through their formations!
Make sure the medical units are well supplied
with medical ninja tools!
Contact Ao and the Sensory unit. Have them hurry!
（ガイ）青春はまぶしさだ　リー！
（リー）わかりました　ガイ先生！
Tsuchikage, these were finished while you were away.
しかし　これ以上　輝くとしたら…。
あっ！　そうか。
Take it.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Assemble! Allied Shinobi Forces!"
ガイ先生　僕は
より　まぶしくなりました。
Assemble! Allied Shinobi Forces!
今日は　キューティクルがまぶしいぞ。
Headbands for the Allied Shinobi Forces, eh? Nice work!
でも　これは　偽りのまぶしさです。
本当のまぶしさは…。
うわっ！　まぶしすぎる！！
目玉焼きも焼けます！
ROCK LEE'S SILLY CHRONICLES
PART 4
うますぎ！　チョー！！
キミたちも　どうです？
To shine bright is youth, Lee!
I understand, Guy Sensei!
（２人）いらん！
But how can I shine even brighter?
＜季節の鍋が大好きな豆助＞
Oh, I know!
Guy Sensei,
I'm even more shiny today!
≫はーい　お待たせ
お鍋できたわよ～
Yes, your hair is so shiny!
But this is just superficial brightness!
This is true brightness!
Whoa! That's just too dazzling!
I can make eggs
sunny-side up too!
＜　それは　つるっとした
つるっとした食感とともに→
It's so good!
You guys want some?
– No thanks!
Tune in again